# 这是晚上9点钟的餐馆
This is the look of this restaurant at 9 PM.
# 这是快10点钟的餐馆 一下子这么多人
It’s about 10 pm, suddenly the place is full of people.
# 他们是来吃什么的
What did they come here for?
# 原来是猪杂粥 这么神奇吗
It’s pork offal congee. Is it this amazing?
# 我也要来试一试
I am gonna try it too.
# 佛山·顺德
拍摄于1月份
Foshan· Shunde
Filmed in January.
# 你好 是在这边点吗
Hello, order food here?
# 直接拿着号就可以了
Take the number then it’s all fine.
# 9点50开始有是吧
Starts at 9:50 PM, doesn't it?
# 这边正在处理（很少的猪杂）
Offal is being prepared here. (small portion of the offal)
# 我们是15号
We are No.15
# 走了 我们坐着去等着吧
Let’s go. We sit there and wait.
# 这边是一个人都没有
No people here.
# 大家都是拿了牌子之后就走了
They all left after taking their number.
# 要不然的话 等的时间太长了
Otherwise the waiting time is too long.
# 我们先坐下来吧
Let’s sit down first.
# 为了吃猪杂 大家都是提前到的
To have pork offal, people all choose to come here before opening.
# 但是呢 像我们这种没有准备的可能就是
Unfortunately, people like us, unprepared, always be like,
# 眼巴巴地
Getting bored easily.
# 看着天 看着地 看着手机
Look around, or check the phone. Feeling empty.
# 但是有准备的会怎么着
But for those experienced diners,
# 带着扑克来
They've brought playing cards with them.
# 好久没有出来吃宵夜了
It’s been a really long time since the last time we had late-night snacks.
# 坐下 竟然会觉得开始困了
I feel sleepy after sitting here for a while.
# 可是我还要等好几个小时
But I still have to wait for a couple more hours.
# 吃猪杂到底有多曲折呢
How much does one have to go through to have this offal congee?
# 就是他们这边是8点左右杀好猪
Usually, the pigs are slaughtered at around 8 pm at the slaughter house.
# 然后司机师傅（老板）呢 赶100多公里
And the driver (restaurant owner) drives over 100 kilometers,
# 送来新鲜的猪杂
to deliver the super fresh pork offal.
# 这个时候差不多是10点钟 再处理好
The arrival time is around 10 pm. And offal is then processed for cooking
# 我们能够吃上可能得11点
We might have to wait until 11 pm to have offal congee finally on our table.
# 所以呢 在座的各位都会等两三个小时
So, everyone here is gonna to wait for 2 or 3 hours.
# 就为这一口猪杂
Only for the taste of the pork offal.
# 9：30左右 大家位置进行了调整
能拼桌的都会拼桌
Around 9:30, the seating plan is arranged.
Customers have to share the table.
# 在10点还没有到来之前
Right before 10 pm,
# 会有一个大总管安排大家拼一下桌
There will be a manager who helps customers get seated
# 然后呢 拿来一个牌子
And, he will bring you a plate.
# 问你有没有什么不吃的
And ask you if there's any ingredient that you don't eat.
# 不吃的话 要提前记下来
Note down any dietary restrictions
# 有的人 可能会不吃猪肺啊
Some of the customers might not like pork lung.
# 有的人 可能不吃猪肝啊 可能都会有
Some may not like pork liver. Anything is possible
# 告诉他们 你不吃什么 剩下的都交给他们
Tell them what you don’t wanna have and let them handle the rest.
# 准备工作 让猪血凝固
Prep work. Coagulate the pig blood.
# 制作猪血的过程
This is the process of preparing the pig blood.
# 白粥出锅
Rice congee is done.
# 煮沸后三到四分钟关火 先吃猪肝
Turn off the heat 3 or 4 minutes after boiling. Eat pig liver first.
# 你这也是煮开了三到四分钟关火就行了
Same for you.
# 时不时地搅拌一下 不要叫它粘锅底了
Occasionally stir the congee, otherwise the congee will stick to the bottom.
# 这个就是先上来了一锅的白粥
Rice congee is served first.
# 然后是送了韭菜猪红汤
Then here comes the pig blood soup with Chinese chive.
# 拿来了酱油姜丝碟
Here comes dipping sauce of soy sauce and ginger.
# 后来服务员把这些猪杂直接放进去
And then the waiter will put the pork offal into the pot.
# 这次确实没有讲究什么顺序
This time we don’t care much about the order of the ingredients.
# 就是直接一股脑地放进去
Just put them in all together.
# 告诉我们 粥开后三四分钟
And the waiter tells us, keep boiling for 3 to 4 mins,
# 然后搅和搅和 就可以吃了
Stir it a bit, then it’s ready to eat.
# 现在是23点15分左右
Now it’s 23 : 15 pm.
# 一边喝着热气腾腾的粥
We are having this warm pig offal congee,
# 一边竟然在这儿流汗
And keep sweating.
# 滑嫩的猪血
The pig blood is tender.
# 汤可以 还有韭菜放在里面提鲜
Soup is fine. Chinese chive enhances the umami taste
# 但是猪血 不知道为什么
But for the pig blood, I don’t know why.
# 我觉得它
I feel that
# 已经超过了我的咸度的承受范围了
it is too salty for my taste
# 还是吃我们的猪杂粥吧
Let’s eat the congee instead.
# 突然在众多的猪杂当中 发现了猪腰
I found a piece of pig kidney among those pig offals.
# 吃一口还是觉得很鲜嫩的
The taste is still so fresh and tender.
# 我的前后两桌都吃完了
The two tables next to me have finished their meal.
# 又来了一桌新客人
Here come a few new customers.
# 现在是23点43分
Now it’s 23:43 pm.
# 听说来吃猪杂粥的人 到凌晨4点才会褪去
I’v heard that customers will keep coming all the way until 4 am.
# 我们要回去睡觉了 真的是困了
We have to go home and get some sleep. I am really sleepy.
# 一桌猪杂已经卖了这么多了 几乎卖完
The pig offal has almost sold out.
# 年纪大了
熬不了夜了
I m too old to stay up this late.
# 关 注
雪 鱼 探 店
Remember to follow our Xue Yu Tan Dian channel ^_^